<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on Louis Lefebvre</title><link>https://louislefebvre.net/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on Louis Lefebvre</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>louislefebvre1999@gmail.com (Louis Lefebvre)</managingEditor><webMaster>louislefebvre1999@gmail.com (Louis Lefebvre)</webMaster><copyright>2023 Louis LeFebvre</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:08:53 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://louislefebvre.net/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring Dual Bluetooth Roles on One Device</title><link>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/containerized-bluetooth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:08:53 -0600</pubDate><author>louislefebvre1999@gmail.com (Louis Lefebvre)</author><guid>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/containerized-bluetooth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, I am going to attempt to &lt;a href="https://medium.com/omi-uulm/how-to-run-containerized-bluetooth-applications-with-bluez-dced9ab767f6">containerize a bluetooth application&lt;/a> using
Docker. I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href="https://louislefebvre.net/tech/simple-bluetooth/">learning about the bluetooth protocol using Go&lt;/a> and simply copy the Go Central code to my
raspberry pi and run it with Go and Bluez. It works, but it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to
transport since it typically requires the hard-coding of the wifi network into
the pi image. Since I travel around a lot, this should be more flexible and
allow me to publish the container so I can pull it down from any machine(that
runs a container runtime).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple Bluetooth Communication Using Go</title><link>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/simple-bluetooth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 14:23:59 -0600</pubDate><author>louislefebvre1999@gmail.com (Louis Lefebvre)</author><guid>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/simple-bluetooth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just going to go over communicating over bluetooth in Go. Over the summer, I had
spent some time learning the &lt;a href="https://learn.adafruit.com/introduction-to-bluetooth-low-energy/gap">basics of bluetooth&lt;/a> and made a super simple
central and peripheral example in Go. Summarizing those learnings here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Definitely go over the above link to help understand the rest of this quick
summary. I seem to frequently mess with bluetooth a bit and then don&amp;rsquo;t touch it
for an extended period of time, so this is mostly a reference document for me to
get a quick refresher on the basics until I spend significant time at the
embedded level. Honestly, I spend way more time at the infrastructure and server
level, so that comes more naturally to me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wireless Interface Information using nl80211/Arch Install</title><link>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/nl80211/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>louislefebvre1999@gmail.com (Louis Lefebvre)</author><guid>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/nl80211/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just copying this over from one of my previous projects. It goes over my
experience with low-level network programming using Linux network interfaces and
Go. Along the way, I was having issues battling &lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Tools/NetworkManager">Network Manager&lt;/a> when I had
Fedora Linux installed, so I switched over to Arch and decided to just use
&lt;a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Iwd">iwd&lt;/a> instead. It has proven to be must better in my experience and
essentially remains out of the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Guess what? Not a whole lot of documentation for nl80211! Yayyyyy :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCNA Journey - Introduction to TCP/IP Networking</title><link>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/ccna-chp1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 14:17:49 -0600</pubDate><author>louislefebvre1999@gmail.com (Louis Lefebvre)</author><guid>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/ccna-chp1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Chapter 1 starts off with getting some initial perspectives on networking down
as a general introduction. This was all really review as they just talked about
the different ways and individual or enterprise connect to a network and through
which mediums.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After an initial network introduction, the reading went into the TCP/IP
networking model and the history of the initial battle between the OSI model and
TCP/IP. The important historical value to note is that in the late 1970s and
early 1980s, the OSI model looked to be the model that would win out. That is
why you see lots of documentation still reference &amp;ldquo;Layer 7&amp;rdquo; protocols even
though the TCP/IP model won out and only technically has 5 layers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Playground for Network Interfaces</title><link>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/network-interfaces/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>louislefebvre1999@gmail.com (Louis Lefebvre)</author><guid>https://louislefebvre.net/tech/network-interfaces/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just messing around with network interfaces in an attempt to understand
some of the low-level OS fundamentals. I was led in this direction when
looking at Wireguard&amp;rsquo;s packages and getting a fun,system-level example of
how to run system calls and file descriptors to configure network interfaces
in Go.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wireguards-tun-interface">Wireguard&amp;rsquo;s TUN interface&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Referenced code can be found &lt;a href="https://github.com/louislef299/go-scripts/blob/main/projects/network-interfaces/main.go">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="setting-up">Setting Up&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The TUN interface is created at &lt;code>/dev/net/tun&lt;/code> and represents the tunnel
used to communicate with the external service. When running through
Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/virtual-networking-101-understanding-tap/">Understanding TUN/TAP&lt;/a>, it made more sense that this TUN
device represented a local point-to-point connection with the Wireguard
service. Found this fun rhyme to remember the difference between the device
types:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>